

Ugur Erdem Seyfi

🗘 kugurerdem 🔗 rugu.dev 🖾 ugur@rugu.dev in ugur-erdem-seyfi 🗣 Eskisehir, TR

Summary _

A **full-stack software developer** with an academic background of **Mathematics** and **Computer Science**. Have been professionally **building Software Products since 2021**, with an exposure to programming since high school in 2015. Embraces a hacker mindset, prioritizing deep understanding, continuous learning, rational thinking, and problem-solving for high-quality product delivery and also, writes a lot.

Education

BS Bilkent University, Mathematics (Full Scholarship)

2018 to 2022

4 months

Have also completed the **entire Computer Science curriculum** through electives.

Experience _____

Sphera Engineering ☑, Software Engineer, Contractor Stack: Postgres, SAML Protocol, Javascript, React, Fastify, Heroku, Cloudflare Pages.

Italy, Florence Dec. 2023 to Apr. 2024

- Developed a **backend infrastructure** and **frontend interface** for global and local administrators to manage designers, products, catalogs, etc.
- Implemented SAML Authentication endpoints, transforming the backend into a SAML Service Provider that works with Salesforce and Azure SAML IdP Services.

Blackwater Information Services, Software Engineer, Contractor Stack: NodeJS, ITCH, GLIMPSE & OUCH Socket Protocols, Electron, React

Turkey, Istanbul Feb. 2023 to Dec. 2023 10 months

- Developed **NodeJS adaptors** for ITCH, GLIMPSE , and OUCH Socket Protocols, protocols that are mostly used for high-frequency trading and market data transmission for central exchanges like Nasdaq and Borsa Istanbul (BIST).
- The NodeJS adaptors that he built passed BIST's OUCH Certification Exam, resulting in the company's listing as one of the few OUCH Certified Applications
- Built higher-level clients on top of the adaptors mentioned above. These clients initiate trading algorithms, check balances and order states, and subscribe to specific order book events for designated markets.
- Developed a REPL program as an interface to trading related functionalities, later built
 another desktop application to tailor traders' needs as a more comfortable front-end
 alternative.

Referencehood ☑, Software Developer, Contractor Stack: Postgres, LevelDB, Redis, bullMQ, NodeJS, Fastify, React, Heroku, Cloudflare Pages

Developed an Automatic Withdrawal system where withdrawal jobs are put into a
Redis-based message queue as soon as the user creates a withdrawal request, and
are handled by consumer processes. Have also implemented a notification system
where GitHub issues are created in case programmatically unrecoverable errors
occur (such as the balance of the wallet becoming insufficient).

Turkey, Istanbul Jan. 2023 to Oct. 2023 9 months

- Created an Admin Panel for operators and support team, enabling access to statistics and user details.
- Built the **first iteration of the Referencehood frontend** which is now present.
- Developed scripts and infrastructure for **parsing reports from crypto exchanges**, and implemented a panel for operators to utilize this infrastructure.
- Migrated the **PostgreSQL database** for improved balance calculation.
- Enhanced public API endpoints.
- Developed NodeJS adaptors for Binance, Okex, and Bybit for sweeping process.
- Provided soft skills for email support, FAQ enhancement, and exchange affairs.

Metavest ☑, Software Engineer, Employee

Stack: NodeJS, Redis, MongoDB, Web3 Libraries, Grafana, Retool, Docker

British Virgin Islands Oct. 2021 to Aug. 2022

- Have developed a monitoring system that aggregates data from DeFi platforms.
- 10 months
- Involved in the process of onboarding new employees to DeFi ecosystem.

Meteksan Defense ☑, Software Engineer, Intern

Turkey, Ankara

 Learned about C++, socket programming, multi-threading, machine learning, and computer vision concepts. Developed a multi-client server network infrastructure and created an AI program for recognizing MNIST numbers.

Jun. 2021 to Jul. 2021 1 month

Projects ____

YieldYak Farmer ☑ 2021

Built the entire application, which took advantage of a temporary opportunity on the Yield Yak platform, resulting in approximately **10k USD in profits** in less than 20 days.

Achievements

Inzva Online Programming Contest 2022 2: 3rd place among 113 teams.

METU Annual Programming Contest 2022 2: 12th place among 100+ teams.

Technologies _____

Javascript: Feeling at home using Javascript. Using it since high school, both for recreational and professional tasks, in **backend and frontend development** projects. Familiar with most of the mainstream libraries including **React ecosystem, Fastify, Lodash**, and many others.

DB Systems: Extensive experience with **PostgreSQL**, the primary choice of database for project development. Also familiar with **Redis, MongoDB, LevelDB, Prometheus**, with a good understanding of each.

Linux/Unix: Been using the **Arch Linux** distribution as his main OS since 2021. Administered numerous **Debian and Ubuntu systems on various servers** to host applications. Knows lots of different **UNIX tools**.

Git: Quite comfortable using git. Regularly uses its CLI and has a good understanding of how it works.

Docker: Familiar with Docker and containerization concepts. Been using containers mostly in his personal environment as well as some of the projects he worked on.

Other: Regularly use **Bash** on personal and administrated systems. Also used **Python, Java, C++**, and **C** for recreational activities and university projects in the past.